Guide to the Carey Chenoweth Shuart Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Carey Chenoweth Shuart Papers
1985-2009
02/2005-002
Shuart, Carey Chenoweth
3.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Mrs. Shuart’s papers are organized into three sections. The collection documents contributions to the University of Houston and contains materials relevant to her interests dating back to the mid 1980’s.
Biographical Information:
Carey Chenoweth Shuart, a Houston native, is well known in the University of Houston community for her volunteer endeavors and welcome donations. She has been instrumental in initiating many positive changes and developments at the University. In 1991, she joined a steering committee of UH volunteers who established and edited the UFriends newsletter for UH Community circulation. She successfully advocated for the Honor’s Program to become the Honor’s College in 1992, and founded and served on its advisory board for almost six years.
Most recently, Carey Shuart was a founder and President of Friends of the UH Women’s Studies Program from 1992 to 1999 and currently serves on the Friends of Women’s Studies Advisory Board. She played a significant role, in conjunction with Cynthia Freeland, the original WOST Director, and her successor Elizabeth Gregory, in the financial development, growth and advancement of the UH Women’s Studies Program and the establishment and funding of the thriving Women’s Archive and Research Center (WARC).
Mrs. Shuart has been acquainted with a number of interesting and productive women, including the late Governor Ann Richards, the late UH President Marguerite Ross Barnett and the late columnist Molly Ivins. She was a member Ann Richards’ Leadership Council in 1991. A member of the UH External Relations Committee under the first woman President Marguerite Ross Barnett, Shuart inherited Dr. Barnett’s presidential desk upon her untimely death in 1992.
Carey Shuart’s dedication and generosity to the University of Houston continue to be made manifest with abundant volunteer service and timely donations. These have been acknowledged with the 1992 Outstanding Volunteer Award from the Division of University Relations and the Alumni Chair’s Award from the University of Houston Alumni Association in 2009. This very good friend of WARC in particular and UH in general has also been recognized in Who’s Who in American Women, Who’s Who in America, and Who’s Who in the World.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston
Genre/Form of Material:
Brochures; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Memorabilia; Periodicals; Photographs
Personal Name:
Shuart, Carey Chenoweth
Topical Term:
Philanthropists -- Texas -- Houston; Voluntarism; Women philanthropists -- Texas -- Houston
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research
Scope and Contents
Mrs. Shuart’s papers are organized into three sections. The collection documents contributions to the University of Houston and contains materials relevant to her interests dating back to the mid 1980’s. Her efforts as a working member of several University of Houston committees and boards are extensively represented. Mrs. Shuart’s papers also lay testament to her acquaintances with a number of very effective women such as Molly Ivins, Ann Richards, Renu Khator and Marguerite Ross Barnett among many others. Additionally, the papers contains various memorabilia collected by Shuart throughout the years, such as mementos from the 100th Anniversary Olympics in Atlanta, Georgia and from her years as a fan of the Houston Comets, a winning woman’s basketball team.
Detailed List of Contents
- Personal
  - Governor Ann Richards
    - The Texas State Bar’s 9th Annual Women and the Law Section Installation Keynote Address (Cassette tape), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and Greeting Cards, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Inaugural Invitation, Programs, Gala and Photograph, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Governor’s Leadership Council, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Governor Ann Richards’ New Texas News (Volume 1, No. 1-4), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Inaugural Celebration Sweatshirt, 1991 (Box 3, Item 1)
    - Ann Richards for Governor Sign (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 1)
  - Molly Ivins, 1944-2007
    - Memorial Service and Events, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Articles and Photograph, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence regarding Ivins, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Texas Observers, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Memorabilia
    - Correspondence regarding the “Library for Women Papers”, 1991, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, n.d., 1998, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1991, 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Event Invitations and Programs, 1991, 1999, 2002, 2004, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Thank-you and Greeting Cards, n.d., 1985-1986, 1994-1996, 2003-2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Emily’s List 10th Annual Majority Council Conferences (videotape), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Autographed Anne Wilkes Tucker Article, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Nobel Laureate Bob Curl Event Photographs, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - New York Trip with Anne Jacobson, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Western Union Telegram from State Bar of Texas President Joyce Cox, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - University of Houston Academic Records, Honor Society Certificate and Resume, 1990-1991, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - James A. Baker II Institute for Public Policy’s Building Dedication Commemorative Plate, 1997 (Box 3, Item 2)
    - University of Houston Glass Paper Weights (Box 3, Item 3)
    - Commemorative 1996 Nobel Prize in Chemistry Give to Dell Butcher (Box 3, Item 4)
    - Historical Houston Chronicles and Indiana Daily Times, 1918, 1929, 1941 (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 2)
    - Child Drawings and Paintings (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 3)
    - Well Test Print (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 4)
    - Discovery Well Print (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 5)
- University of Houston
  - Friends of the University of Houston (UFriends)
    - Meeting Agendas, Reports and Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - UFriends Newsletter, 1992-1998 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1992 Volunteer of the Year “Dollar Bill” Award (Box 3, Item 5)
    - University of Houston Department of Art Poster (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 6)
  - Friends of the University of Houston Women’s Studies Program
    - Organization Facts and History, 1991-2001 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bylaws, 1997, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Meeting Agendas, Reports, and Member Lists, 1997-2006 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 2001, 2004, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Event Invitations and Programs, n.d., 1993, 1997-2001, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Table Talks - Event Information and Articles, 1998-2000, 2002, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Table Talks - Photographs, 1998, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Women’s Studies Program - Program Information and Facts, 1991-2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Women’s Studies Program - Faculty and Student Scholarships, Fellowships and Prizes, 1997-1998, 2000-2003, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Women’s Studies Program - Event Information, 1992, 1999, 2001, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Women’s Studies Program - Motherhood and Families Materials, n.d.,1991, 2004-2005, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Women’s Studies Program - New Voices Newsletter, 1996-2008 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Women’s Archives and Research Center (WARC), n.d., 1994-1995, 1997, 1999-2001, 2006, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Friends of Visual Studies/ School of Art Partners (SOAP)
    - Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, n.d., 1993-1994, 2003, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Event Invitations, Programs and Photographs, n.d., 1999, 2003, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Exhibitions Reviews, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Brochures (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Blaffer Gallery Advisory Board
    - Meeting Minutes, Financial Records, Reports and Correspondence, 2003-2008 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Exhibitions’ Promotional Materials and Invitations, n.d., 2003-2005, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Articles, 2003-2005, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Newsline Newsletters, 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - The Honors College at the University of Houston Advisory Board
    - Meeting Minutes, Reports and Correspondence, 1991-1995, 2004, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Event Invitations, Programs and Articles, 1991-2008 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Other Campus Resources and Events
    - Texas Center for Superconductivity Events, 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - The Mary Comeaux Women’s Resource Center Brochure (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - President Marguerite Ross Barnett - Articles, Papers and Photograph, 1992, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - President Marguerite Ross Barnett - Replacement Search Articles, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Selection and Investiture of President and Chancellor Renu Khator, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - John J. Moores Contribution and the Moores School of Music Society Grand Opening, 1991,1997 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence
    - Board of Regents, Chancellors, Presidents, and Vice Presidents, 1991-1993, 1995, 2004-2009 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Office of the Dean, 2003, 2006-2008 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Graduate College of Social Work and Nobel Women’s Initiative, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2005-2009 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Invitations and Thank-you and Greeting Cards
    - Event Invitations and Programs, 1991, 1999, 2002-2009 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Thank-you and Greeting Cards, n.d., 1993, 1995, 2001-2002, 2004-2008 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Periodicals and Reports
    - President’s Report, 1991, 1995, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - The Daily Cougar, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - A University Report on Partnerships, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Collegium: The Magazine of the University of Houston, 1997, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - It’s Our Minds that Matter: The Economic Impact of Higher Education, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Articles, n.d., 1991, 1997-1998, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Material
    - Melcher House Event, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Thank-you Breakfast for Employees and Administrators that Assisted with the Ezekiel Cullen Building Fire Clean-up, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Betty Frieden Reception, Cynthia Freeland Retirement Party, Ruth Simmons Event (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 100th Anniversary Olympics in Atlanta
  - Memorabilia
    - Hotel Accommodations, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Tickets, Schedules, Calendar, Maps, Pin, Guide, 1996, 2005, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Souvenir Straw Hat (Box 3, Item 6)
    - “Original ‘Piece’ of the Atlanta Olympic Track” Mounted Poster (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 7)
    - Commemorative Seat Cushion (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 8)
    - America True Flag (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 9)
  - Newspaper Sections
    - Houston Chronicle, July 14, 1996 (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 10)
    - Houston Chronicle, New York Times and The Atlanta Journal-Constitution, July 28, 1996 (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 11)
    - Houston Chronicle and The Atlanta Journal-Constitution, July 29, 1996 (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 12)
    - Houston Chronicle and The Atlanta Journal-Constitution, July 30, 1996 (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 13)
    - Houston Chronicle and The Atlanta Journal-Constitution, July 31, 1996 (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 14)
    - Houston Chronicle, August 1-5, 1996 (Ovs box 4, Ovs folder 15)
  - Periodicals
    - U.S. News and World Report, July 15- July 22 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Sports Illustrated: Olympic Preview Issue, July 22, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Sports Illustrated: Olympic Daily, Day 1, Day 7- Day 10 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Sports Illustrated: Olympic Daily, Day 11 –Day 15 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Sports Illustrated, August 5, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Time, August 5, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)